<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[JCU Robo Club]]></title>
  <link href="http://jcuroboclub.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://jcuroboclub.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-03-27T13:50:03+10:00</updated>
  <id>http://jcuroboclub.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[JCU Robo Club]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[jcurobotics@gmail.com]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[NQRoS]]></title>
    <link href="http://jcuroboclub.github.io/blog/2015/03/25/nqros/"/>
    <updated>2015-03-25T13:01:39+10:00</updated>
    <id>http://jcuroboclub.github.io/blog/2015/03/25/nqros</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The North Queensland Robotic Sumo (NQRoS) competition is a student robotics competition aimed to foster student involvement in robotics, and intelligent systems. The competition focuses on rewarding innovation in sensing and intelligence. Held in Townsville, the competition is not limited to North Queenslanders and aims to involve entrants from across Australia and further.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>Students from across Australia will compete in a Mini-class Robotic Sumo competition, as per the official RoboGames unified sumo robot rules, using the <a href="https://www.pololu.com/category/129/zumo-robots-and-accessories">Pololu Zumo</a> robotics platform. Students may not modify the driving hardware, but are encouraged to modify their systems to be more intelligent with smart sensors.</p>

<p>Cash prizes valued at $1000, $500 and $200 will be awarded for 1st, 2nd and 3rd. The competition, hosted by James Cook University, will be held Fri May 22nd 2015 in Townsville.</p>

<h2>Rules</h2>

<h3>Eligibility</h3>

<p>Eligible competitors are:</p>

<ul>
<li>children under the age of 18,</li>
<li>current students, or</li>
<li>undergraduate/postgraduate adults not employed in the robotics industry.</li>
</ul>


<p>The definition of &ldquo;robotics industry &#8220;is deemed by the event organizers in order to keep within the spirit of the competition of non-professionals.
There may be no more than 3 entrants representing a participating organisation. Please RSVP by 22nd April to <a href="mailto:ashley.gillman@my.jcu.edu.au">Ashley Gillman</a> to enter.</p>

<h3>Competition Format</h3>

<p>The event is a robot sumo match, as defined in the RoboGames Unified Sumo Robot Rules (herein RoboGames Rules) Section 1. The event rules are consistent with those outlined in the RoboGames Rules, available <a href="http://robogames.net/rules/all-sumo.php" title="RoboGames sumo rules">here</a>.</p>

<h3>Further Requirements for Robots</h3>

<p>Robots are required to meet RoboGames Autonomous Mini Sumo Class (i.e., 10 cm x 10 cm base, unlimited height, 500 g maximum weight). One exception is made to the RoboGames Rules Section 3.3: the method of control must be fully autonomous with no human intervention (apart from starting), however control need not be contained within the robot. That is, off-board processing is allowed. In addition to requirements outlined in RoboGames Rules Section 3, a number of further requirements are placed on the robots.</p>

<p>All entry robots shall be based on the <a href="https://www.pololu.com/category/129/zumo-robot-and-accessories" title="Pololu Zumo">Pololu Zumo kit</a>. Any of the v1.0, v1.1, v1.2 or the 32U4 models are acceptable.</p>

<p>The power source may be modified, however the power source(s) must be contained within the standard Zumo battery housing. Further modifications to the Zumo are encouraged, especially the inclusion of addition sensors, servos, and computational capacity.</p>

<h3>Judging</h3>

<p>A total of three judges shall be nominated, representing:</p>

<ul>
<li>the hosting university,</li>
<li>an attending university, and</li>
<li>a competition sponsor.</li>
</ul>


<p>Of the three, one shall be nominated as chief judge, and another as the floor judge.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Welcome]]></title>
    <link href="http://jcuroboclub.github.io/blog/2015/03/24/welcome/"/>
    <updated>2015-03-24T23:15:48+10:00</updated>
    <id>http://jcuroboclub.github.io/blog/2015/03/24/welcome</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Welcome to James Cook University&rsquo;s Robo Club, run by the IEEE Student Branch.</p>

<!--more-->


<p>Watch this space for more information.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
